[0]Aggiunte le Tips Words
[1][color index="800000"]『[color index="820000"]
[2][color index="800000"]』 e’ stato aggiunto ai Tips.
[3]‘
[4]’
[5] 
[6]No Dati
[7]???
[8]Nr.
[9]/
[10] 
[11] 
[12] 
[13] 
[14] 
[15] 
[16] 
[17] 
[18]Nuovi
[19]Non letti
[20]A-C
[21]D-F
[22]G-I
[23]J-L
[24]M-O
[25]P-S
[26]T-V
[27]W-Z
[28]0-9
[29]Simbolo
[30]Nuovi
[31]Non letti
[32]ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZ0123456789@β
[33]aAbBcCdDeEfFgGhHiIjJkKlLmMnNoOpPqQrRsStTuUvVwWxXyYzZ0123456789@β
[34]Chuunibyou
[35]Cronaca dell’Akasha
[36]Cronaca dell’Akasha
[37]cronaca dell’akasha
[38]Il database in cui ogni evento nell’intero universo dal passato al futuro viene registrato. La memoria della coscienza collettiva dell’umanita’. Non in vinile.
[39]Altro
[40]Acetilcolina
[41]Acetilcolina
[42]acetilcolina
[43]Un neurotrasmettitore. I livelli di Acetilcolina nell’ippocampo aumentano quando si apprende o si ricorda.
[44]Altro
[45]Ayamein
[46]Ayamein
[47]ayamein
[48](Non reale) L’Accademia Femminile di Ayamein. Una scuola privata per ragazze nel quartiere Kudanshita di Tokyo. Come potenza accademica, Ayamein e’ una destinazione popolare per gli studenti stranieri.
[49]Altro
[50]Alpaca
[51]Alpaca
[52]alpaca
[53]Un mammifero. Legato al cammello. Peso medio: 50-55kg Lunghezza media: Circa 2m Habitat: Peru, Bolivia, Chile. Recentemente, gli alpaca possono essere trovati anche in America e Nuova Zelanda. A differenza dei cammelli, gli alpaca non hanno gobbe. I loro corpi sono coperti da un pelo morbido. A causa dei loro strani colli lunghi e volti affascinanti, hanno un po’ di popolarita’ come un animale brutto-ma-carino (carinuccio).
[54]Internet
[55]Ancora
[56]Ancora
[57]ancora
[58]Per collegarsi a uno specifico post di un forum, tipicamente come risposta. Su @channel, viene creata scrivendo “>>NUMEROPOST”. Alcune volte, le persone si impegnano del “gioco delle ancore”, un gioco dove il postatore lascia una decisione a chiunque posti con il numero di post collegato, tipicamente scelto 20-30 post prima. Per esempio, “>>1000 dara’ il nome al mio primogenito.”
[59]Internet
[60]Anzai-sensei
[61]Anzai-sensei
[62]anzai-sensei
[63]Il coach di un famoso manga sul basket. Su internet, i postatori alcune volte esprimono un disperato desiderio citando il manga cosi’: “Anzai-sensei, voglio __.” Un’altra frase spesso citata, pronunciata da Anzai-sensei, e’: “Se ti arrendi, e’ game over.”
[64]Internet
[65]Contro
[66]Hater
[67]contro
[68]Persone che scrivono commenti negativi su qualcosa o qualcuno su internet. Appaiono in luoghi dove si riuniscono i fan di quelle cose o persone, e li provocano scrivendo cose offensive. Non e’ raro da parte loro causare una discussione accesa tra i fan.
[69]Altro
[70]Il Principio di Causalita’
[71]Il Principio di Causalita’
[72]il principio di causalita’
[73]Un principio scientifico e filosofico che afferma che ogni singolo evento ha una causa, ed e’ da quella causa che viene prodotto un effetto. La teoria della relativita’ e’ fondata su questo principio. Tuttavia, i fisici quantistici hanno osservato fenomeni su micro-scala che non sembrano obbedire il principio di causalita’.
[74]Internet
[75]Wizard
[76]Wizard
[77]wizard
[78]Un hacker incredibilmente abile.
[79]Scienza
[80]Effetto Urashima
[81]Effetto Urashima
[82]effetto urashima
[83]Nella Relativita’ Ristretta, a fenomeno che nasce dal fatto che il tempo rallenta mentre un oggetto si avvicina alla velocita’ della luce. Per esempio, immagina che un astronautaa viaggi facendo andata e ritorno da una stella vicino alla velocita’ della luce. Questo viaggio potrebbe richiedere qualche anno dal punto di vista dell’astronauta, ma nel momento in cui tornera’ sulla Terra saranno passati migliaia di anni senza la sua assenza.
[84]Chuunibyou
[85]Urd
[86]Urd
[87]urd
[88]La piu’ anziana delle tre Norne (dee del destino) nella mitologia Norrena. Le tre sorelle si occupano dell’Albero del Mondo, Yggdrasil, che ha anche radici nel Pozzo di Urd. Urd e’ la Norna del Passato.
[89]Internet
[90]Dr.Excite
[91]Excite-sensei
[92]dr.excite
[93]Un sito per la traduzione automatica.
[94]Altro
[95]Exa-
[96]Exa-
[97]exa-
[98]10[¹⁸]. Prefixes are Kilo -> Mega -> Giga -> Tera -> Peta -> Exa in ordine crescente di grandezza. 1 exa = 1 quintilione.
[99]Chuunibyou
[100]ECHELON
[101]ECHELON
[102]echelon
[103]In base ai complottisti, Echelon e’ un sistema di intercettazione avanzata dei segnali con sede negli Stati Uniti e gestito dalla National Security Agency (NSA). Tuttavia, le autorita’ americane non hanno mai pubblicamente confermato l’esistenza di Echelon, e non e’ mai stata trovata nessuna prova della sua esistenza. I paesi partecipanti includono presumibilmente il Regno Unito, Canada, Australia, e Nuova Zelanda, ma non Francia.
[104]Come alleato degli Stati Uniti, il Giappone puo’ permettere la costruzione di stazioni Echelon locali in cambio dell’accesso ai dati intercettati. L’array di antenne chiamato “gabbia da elefante” localizzato dentro la Misawa Air Base ad Aomori, Giappone si dice che sia una di queste stazioni. Si dice che queste stazioni possano intercettare, collezionare, e analizzare un’ampia gamma di segnali, incluse trasmissioni private dei cellulari.
[105]Chuunibyou
[106]Eldhrimnir
[107]Eldhrimnir
[108]eldhrimnir
[109]Nella mitologia Norrena, il calderone usato per cucinare per gli dei.
[110]Chuunibyou
[111]Eterocromia
[112]Eterocromia
[113]eterocromia
[114]Heterochromia iridis, una condizione dove gli occhi hanno colori diversi. Un tratto spesso trovato in personaggi di anime e manga. Tipicamente non esiste una ragione per cui il personaggio sia eterocromatico. Tipicamente e’ per questione di moe o di figaggine.
[115]Akihabara
[116]Oden in scatola
[117]Oden in scatola
[118]oden in scatola
[119]Un pasto in scatola, venduto nei distributori automatici. Ogni lattina contiene del brodo caldo con vari ingredienti dell’oden come uova bollite, ravanello, konjac, manzo, e tofu. Una popolare specialita’ di Akihabara.
[120]Internet
[121]Incontro offline
[122]ofukai
[123]incontro offline
[124]Quando i membri di una comunita’ di Internet si incontrano nella vita reale.
[125]Altro
[126]Ippocampo
[127]kaiba
[128]ippocampo
[129]Una parte importante del cervelo. L’ippocampo governa la memoria e la navigazione spaziale.
[130]Altro
[131]Ippocampo CA3
[132]Hippocampus Cornu Ammonis Region 3
[133]ippocampo ca3
[134]L’ippocampo e’ diviso in tre sezioni istologiche: CA1, CA2, e CA3. CA si riferisce al nome dato all’ippocampo dall’anatomista Garengeot nel 1742 -- “cornu Ammonis,” il corno di Amun.
[135]Chuunibyou
[136]Consiglio per lo Sviluppo
[137]Consiglio per lo Sviluppo
[138]consiglio per lo sviluppo
[139]Il modo in cui Okarin chiama una festa.
[140]Altro
[141]Teoria del Caos
[142]Teoria del Caos
[143]teoria del caos
[144]La teoria dove anche se qualcosa puo’ essere espresso con una semplice formula, e’ difficile prevedere esattamente il suo risultato. Tuttavia, cio’ non vuol dire che il risultato e’ casuale. Vuol dire che anche la piu’ piccola variazione nelle condizioni iniziali puo’ causare un risultato estremamente divergente. Questa teoria si applica solo a previsioni a lungo termine.
[145]Otaku
[146]Distributore di giocattoli a capsule
[147]Gashapon
[148]gashapon
[149]Un distributore che dispensa piccoli giocattoli in maniera casuale. E’ impossibile dire quale giocattolo sara’ prima di aprire la capsula.
[150]Altro
[151]Crunchy-kun
[152]Garugari-kun
[153]crunchy-kun
[154](Non reale) Un marchio di ghiaccioli. Popolare in tutto il Giappone. Oltre al sapore di soda, vengono vendute altre 50 varieta’, tra le quali cola, uva, e altre sapori promozionali. “Vittoria” puo’ essere scritto su una parte della stecca. Una stecca vincente da’ il diritto di avere un ghiacciolo gratuito. Le possibilita’ di vittoria sembrano intorno al 2%.
[155]Otaku
[156]Gunbam
[157]Mobile Jacket Gunbam
[158]gunbam
[159](Non reale) Formalmente noto come “Mobile Jacket Gunbam”. Un’opera fondamentale degli anime mecha. La prima serie e’ andata in onda verso la fine degli anni 70, e si sono susseguiti molti sequel e spinoff da allora.
[160]Chuunibyou
[161]L’Organizzazione
[162]L’Organizzazione
[163]l’organizzazione
[164]L’Organizzazione e’ l’Organizzazione. Niente di piu’. Niente di meno. Il suo nome ufficiale e’ un altro, ma anche pronunciare quel nome equivale a voler morire. Per quel motivo, tutti coloro che sanno della sua esistenza la chiamano semplicemente l’Organizzazione.
[165]Otaku
[166]Antropomorfismo
[167]Antropomorfismo
[168]antropomorfismo
[169]Rappresentare una entita’ non umana come un personaggio umanoide. Animali ed equipaggiamento militare sono tra i piu’ comuni, ma tutto puo’ essere antropomorfizzato, anche concetti astratti, elementi chimici, e paesi. 
[170]Otaku
[171]Kirari-chan
[172]Kirari-chan
[173]kirari-chan
[174](Non reale) L’eroina di “RaiNet Kakeru”. Il suo nome completo e’ Nishimura Kirari. E’ una ragazza atletica e intelligente in quinta elementare. E’ anche carina e ha un bel carattere. In pratica e’ la ragazza perfetta. Le piace la moda. Odia i funghi.
[175]Altro
[176]King Burger
[177]King Burger
[178]king burger
[179](Non reale) Una popolare catena di fast food in America. Solo pochi franchise esistono in Giappone.
[180]Internet
[181]Cracking
[182]Cracking
[183]cracking
[184]Nel mondo informatico, azioni che includono l’accesso illegale a sistemi di rete e manipolazione dei dati. Spesso e’ confuso con l’hacking, ma hacking inizialmente indicava un studio costruttivo del software. Cracking, invece, e’ una azione maligna.
[185]Altro
[186]Malattia di Creutzfeldt-Jakob
[187]KROITS-felt YA-kob disease
[188]malattia di creutzfeldt-jakob
[189]Un altro nome per encefalopatia spongiforme bovina (BSE, comunemente conosciuta come morbo della mucca pazza), ma usato solo in caso di infezione umana. I primi sintomi includono perdita di memoria, movimenti anomali, cambi di personalita’, demenza, e rigidita’ muscolare. In casi gravi, il paziente potrebbe deperire per 1-2 anni prima di morire di paralisi respiratoria o altre complicazioni.
[190]Altro
[191]Determinismo
[192]Determinismo
[193]determinismo
[194]La scuola di filosofia affermante che ogni evento e’ predeterminato dagli eventi precedenti. Il passato ha determinato il presente; il presente determina il futuro. Anche se pensiamo di agire di nostra volonta’, in verita’, stiamo solo seguendo un percorso predeterminato.
[195]Coloro che credono nel determinismo spesso citano l’esperimento mentale del Demone di Laplace: per “Un intelletto che ad un certo momento conoscesse tutte le forze che mettono le cose in moto, e tutte le posizioni di tutti gli elementi di cui la natura e’ composta (...) niente sarebbe incerto e il futuro proprio come il passato sarebbe presente davanti ai suoi occhi.” --Pierre Simon Laplace
[196]Altro
[197]Gero Froggy
[198]Gero Kaerun
[199]gero froggy
[200](Non reale) Una serie di pupazzi con la maniglia con la presenza di un personaggio brutto-ma-carino (uglycute) a forma di rana diventato popolare tra le ragazze delle superiori a Shibuya un anno fa. Dopo il Terremoto di Shibuya, la serie e’ stata cancellata, e la loro popolarita’ e’ fortemente diminuita.
[201]Internet
[202]La petite mort
[203]sage tempo
[204]la petite mort
[205]Una condizione di rilascio mentale e fisico unica della fisiologia maschile. Caratterizzata da una sensazione di calma e compostezza suprema. Entrare in questo stato equivale a sentirsi come un guscio vuoto. Conosciuto come iper saggio del tempo o santo del tempo.
[206]Gadget Futuristico
[207]Il Fantasma nella Palla
[208]Mobile Armored Riot Camouflauge Ball
[209]il fantasma nella palla
[210]Gadget Futuristico No. 7. Un gadget creato organizzando dodici monitor CRT da 6 pollici in una sfera. Piccole telecamere C-MOS sono installate negli spazi tra i monitor, ognuno connesso al monitor sul lato opposto della sfera. Questo tentativo di camouflage ottico e’ il piu’ grande capolavoro tra i Gadget Futuristici completati, ma la sua enorme grandezza lo rende difficile da conservare.
[211]Il suo nome deriva dal manga scifi “Ghost in the Husk”, con un adattamento anime.
[212]Otaku
[213]Code Jeass
[214]Code Jeass
[215]code jeass
[216](Non reale) Una famosissima serie TV anime trasmessa nel 2006. La storia ruota attorno un giovane uomo che ottiene un occhio magico che puo’ controllare le menti e lo utilizza per far scattare una rivoluzione.
[217]Otaku
[218]Cosplay
[219]Costume Play
[220]cosplay
[221]Una abbreviazione di “costume play.” Vestirsi con un costume, molto spesso di un personaggio fittizio. Le persone che fanno cosplay sono chiamate “cosplayer”, che puo’ essere abbreviato con “’layer.” Molti cosplayer realizzano i propri costumi.
[222]Internet
[223]Non guardarmi
[224]kocchi min’na
[225]non guardarmi
[226]Su internet, e’ una regola non scritta dire questo quando vedi una immagine di qualcuno o qualcosa che guarda verso la telecamera.
[227]Scienza
[228]Interpretazione di Copenaghen
[229]Interpretazione di Copenaghen
[230]interpretazione di copenaghen
[231]Un approccio molto noto all’esperimento mentale del gatto di Schrodinger. In questa interpretazione, prima che venga aperta la scatola, il gatto esiste come combinazione di due funzioni d’onda, una dove e’ “vivo” e l’altra dove e’ “morto”. L’istante in cui la scatola viene aperta e il gatto osservato, la funzione d’onda collassa ad una delle due. Se il gatto e’ vivo alla apertura della scatola, la funzione d’onda collassa per diventare “gatto vivo”. Similmente, se il gatto e’ morto, la funzione d’onda collassa per diventare “gatto morto”.
[232]Un altro approccio quantistico per questo esperimento e’ l’interpretazione a molti mondi. In questo caso, l’osservatore che trova il gatto vivo e l’osservatore che trova il gatto morto esistono due universi separati che divergono nel momento in cui la scatola viene aperta. L’Interpretazione di Copenaghen e’ attualmente la teoria dominante.
[233]Otaku
[234]ComiMa
[235]ComiMa
[236]comiMa
[237](Non reale) Comic Giga Market. Un enorme evento per otaku tenuto due volte all’anno al Tokyo Big Sight. Ad ogni ComiMa, migliaia di artisti si riuniscono per vendere le proprie creazioni, che variano da manga erotici basati su anime popolari a action figures, musica, e giochi. Il prossimo ComiMa sara’ il 15 di Agosto.
[238]Chuunibyou
[239]Spazio di Singolarita’
[240]Spazio di Singolarita’
[241]spazio di singolarita’
[242]Un tipo di magia in cui il suo utilizzatore sovrascrive il mondo con una dimensione parallela basata sulle esperienze emotive dell’utilizzatore. Spesso usato nelle conversazioni ordinarie per parlare di coppie che flirtano in pubblico, immersi nel proprio mondo, fregandosene del dolore che infliggono agli altri.
[243]Otaku
[244]Qualcuno di cosi’ carino non puo’ essere una ragazza
[245]konna kawaii ko ga onnanoko no hazu ga nai
[246]qualcuno di cosi’ carino non puo’ essere una ragazza
[247]E’ una regola non scritta usare questa frase quando vedi qualcuno che sembra una ragazza carina ma o e’ di genere non specificato o e’ in realta’ un ragazzo. Questa espressione e’ anche usata sarcasticamente con ragazze che hanno un aspetto da ragazzo.
[248]Gadget Futuristico
[249]Cyalume Saber
[250]Diphenyl oxalate Saber
[251]cyalume saber
[252]Gadget Futuristico No. 6. Un bastone luminoso rosso con un manico attaccato, permettendo ad uno di afferrarlo come una spada. Reso possibile non solo grazie all’hardware del Laboratorio dei Gadget Futuristici, ma anche grazie al sapere chimico! Ispirato da “Spark Wars,” una serie di film epici scifi.
[253]Altro
[254]Survival Airsoft
[255]survival game
[256]survival airsoft
[257]Una sorta di battaglia usando fucili ad aria. Giocata principalmente fuori nelle montagne. I partecipanti generalmente indossano equipaggiamento camouflage.
[258]Scienza
[259]Congettura di protezione cronologica
[260]Congettura di protezione cronologica
[261]congettura di protezione cronologica
[262]Nella meccanica quantistica, una teoria, proposta da Stephen Hawking, che afferma che il viaggio nel tempo e’ impossibile. Qualsiasi tentativo di viaggiare nel tempo sara’ impedito da effetti quantistici. Completare il viaggio nel tempo richiede infinita “energia di campo”, che e’ impossibile da ottenere. In altre parole, le leggi di causalita’ -- e per estensione, la cronologia o linea temporale dell’universo -- sono protetti dalla meccanica quantistica.
[263]Scienza
[264]Orizzonte degli Eventi
[265]Orizzonte degli Eventi
[266]orizzonte degli eventi
[267]Conosciuto anche come superficie di Schwarzchild. In un buco nero, esiste un punto oltre il quale neanche la luce puo’ sfuggire alla immensa gravita’ del buco nero. Questo confine e’ chiamato the orizzonte degli eventi. Poiche’ luce e altre onde elettromagnetiche sono responsabili per la trasmissione di informazioni, niente di tutto quello che si verifica dentro l’orizzonte degli eventi puo’ essere osservato dall’esterno. Il centro di un buco nero e’ nero perche’ la luce non puo’ fuggire da esso.
[268]Otaku
[269]Death Flag
[270]Death Flag
[271]death flag
[272]Un termine della metanarrazione. Quando un personaggio triggera una death flag, hanno detto o hanno fatto qualcosa che preannuncia la loro morte. Un modo comune per triggerare una death flag consiste nel fare una promessa alla vigilia di una battaglia finale. Per esempio, “Quando terminera’ la guerra, mi sposero’”.
[273]Altro
[274]Chevy
[275]Chevy
[276]chevy
[277](Non reale) Un marchio di automobile Americana.
[278]Altro
[279]Legge di Janet
[280]Legge di Janet
[281]legge di janet
[282]Una prospettiva sul passaggio del tempo proposta dallo psicologo Pierre Janet. Per qualche motivo, mentre una persona invecchia, il tempo sembra passare sempre piu’ velocemente. Per esempio, un anno e’ un settimo della vita di ragazzo di 7 anni, ma solo un settantesimo di una persona di 70 anni. Con questo ragionamente, la lunghezza soggettiva del tempo e’ inversamente proporzionale all’eta’.
[283]Scienza
[284]Gatto di Schrodinger
[285]Gatto di Schrodinger
[286]gatto di schrodinger
[287]Un esperimento mentale proposto dal fisico Erwin Schrodinger. Schrodinger l’aveva pensato come un paradosso per rifiutare la teoria quantistica, but e’ stato dimostrato da allora di non essere un paradosso. Viene spesso riferito nella finzione come esempio della complessita’ della meccanica quantistica.
[288]Un gatto viene inserito in una scatola. La scatola contiene anche una fiala di gas velenoso e un campione di una sostanza radioattiva. Se la sostanza radioattiva emette una particella alfa, fa scattare un sensore, il quale rilascia il gas velenoso e uccide il gatto. Assumere che la sostanza radioattiva abbia il 50% di possibilita’ di emettere una particella alfa per ora. Dopo un’ora, apri la scatola.
[289]Il gatto ha il 50% di possibilita’ di essere vivo oppure morto. La domanda e’, il gatto era vivo o morto prima di scoprirlo? In base ad Einstein, la tua osservazione delle condizioni del gatto e’ irrilevante. Il gatto era sia vivo che morto prima che tu aprissi la scatola.
[290]Scienza
[291]Acceleratore
[292]Acceleratore
[293]acceleratore
[294]Un dispositivo che accelera particelle cariche con l’obiettivo di studiare le reazioni che risultano dalle collisioni di queste particelle. Il tipo di particella accelerata determina anche il nome dell’apparecchiatura. Negli anni recenti, molti ad acceleratori ad alta energia sono stati sincrotoni ad anello.
[295]Gli acceleratori ad anello sono molto costosi da costruire, ma possono performare gli esperimenti piu’ efficaci. Il motivo per la forma ad anello e’ che le particelle cariche possono essere trasmesse attraverso un campo elettromagnetico per piegare la loro traiettoria attraverso la forza di Lorentz. I piu’ grandi sincrotoni al mondo, oltre all’LHC del SERN, si trovano negli USA, nel Regno Unito, e in Giappone.
[296]Otaku
[297]Shota
[298]Shota
[299]shota
[300]Un ragazzo o giovane uomo incredibilmente carino. Questi personaggi sono principalmente progettati per attrarre una demografia femminile.
[301]Altro
[302]John Titor
[303]John Titor
[304]john titor
[305]Un autoproclamato viaggiatore del tempo dal 2036 che e’ apparso in un forum Americano su internet nel Novembre del 2000. L’internet e’ andata in tumulto, riempiendo la bacheca di domande e dibattiti. Titor ha postato immagini della sua macchina del tempo e il suo manuale di controllo, cosi’ come diagrammi che illustravano le meccaniche della macchina del tempo.
[306]Ha anche diffuso informazioni su eventi nell’immediato futuro, la fisica per il viaggio nel tempo, interventi storici, il multiverso, le linee temporali, e le linee di universo. E poi, quattro mesi dopo la sua apparizione, ha lasciato un commento dicendo “Io lasciero’ questa linea di universo a breve e questo sara’ il mio post finale” e poi e’ scomparso.
[307]Altro
[308]Sincronicita’
[309]Sincronicita’
[310]sincronicita’
[311]Una significativa coincidenza. Simultaneita’. La sensazione che due eventi senza alcuna relazione causale abbiano una relazione deterministica significativa. Per esempio, “Un vaso e’ caduto e si e’ spezzato, e allo stesso tempo, mia nonna e’ morta in ospedale”.
[312]Quasi chiunque ha sentito la sincronicita’ in qualche punto della loro vita. Un concetto avanzato dallo psicologo svizzero Carl Jung (1875-1961).
[313]Internet
[314]Donna Mainstream
[315]Donna Mainstream
[316]donna mainstream
[317]Un termine offensivo usato dagli otaku per descrivere donne che seguono un modo di pensare incomprensibile agli uomini. Tali donne sono presumibilmente influenzate dalla cultura “mainstream” promossa dalle riviste per donne. Alcuni affermano che questa frase e’ usata dagli uomini per giustificare la loro mancanza di successo con le donne.
[318]Internet
[319]Super Hacka
[320]Super Hacka
[321]super hacka
[322]Un hacker incredibilmente abile. O almeno qualcuno che afferma di esserlo. La minaccia “il mio amico e’ un hacker, quindi puo’ facilmente capire chi sei” appare spesso durante le discussioni su internet. Le persone chiamano con ironia l’ovviamente non esistente hacker un “hacka”.
[323]Chuunibyou
[324]Skuld
[325]Skuld
[326]skuld
[327]La piu’ giovane delle tre Norne (dee del destino) nella mitologia Norrena. Le tre sorelle si occupano dell’Albero del Mondo, Yggdrasil, che ha anche radici nel Pozzo di Urd. Skuld e’ la Norna del Futuro. Anche una valchiria.
[328]Altro
[329]Starbecks
[330]Sutabe
[331]starbecks
[332](Non reale) Una catena di caffe’.
[333]Otaku
[334]The World
[335]Za Waarudo
[336]the world
[337]Il potere di poter fermare il tempo. Una delle soprannaturali abilita’ delle entita’ chiamate “stand”, che appaiono nel popolare manga Juju’s Bizarre Adventures. Coloro che hanno la capacita’ di poter usare uno stand sono chiamati “portatori di stand”.
[338]Internet
[339]Standalone
[340]Standalone
[341]standalone
[342]Un computer che non e’ connesso a nessun altro computer o rete.
[343]Altro
[344]Slow Food
[345]Slow Food
[346]slow food
[347]Cibo che richiede tempo per essere cucinato e mangiato, opposto al fast food o al cibo istantaneo.
[348]Altro
[349]Ripetizione Elaborativa
[350]Ripetizione Elaborativa
[351]ripetizione elaborativa
[352]Nella psicologia, l’azione di trasferimento dalla memoria a breve termine alla memoria a lungo termine. Cio’ e’ possibile collegando un significato a cio’ che deve essere ricordato, oppure collegandolo a qualche memoria familiare.
[353]Internet
[354]Smex
[355]Sekkuru
[356]smex
[357]Sesso.
[358]Altro
[359]Serendipita’
[360]Serendipita’
[361]serendipita’
[362]L’abilita’ di scoprire qualcosa di valore mentre si cerca qualcos’altro. Il forno a microonde e’ nato grazie alla serendipita’.
[363]Otaku
[364]Zerosum
[365]Zerosum
[366]zerosum
[367](Non reale) Il protagonista di Code Jeass. Lui e’ il “Giovane Nobile della Ribellione” che nasconde la sua identita’ dietro una maschera.
[368]Scienza
[369]Teoria della Relativita’
[370]Teoria della Relativita’
[371]teoria della relativita’
[372]Si riferisce sia teoria della relativita’ speciale di Einstein pubblicata nel 1905, sia alla sua teoria della relativita’ generale pubblicata nel 1916. Rappresentata dalla famosa equazione, E=mc[キリ]2. La teoria della relativita’ speciale e’ definita dai seguenti assiomi: “Gli oggetti non possono viaggiare a una velocita’ maggiore della velocita’ della luce.” “Quando la velocita’ si avvicina alla velocita’ della luce, il passaggio del tempo tende a zero.”
[373]“Quando la velocita’ si avvicina alla velocita’ della luce, la lunghezza tende a zero.” “Quando la velocita’ si avvicina alla velocita’ della luce, la massa tende all’infinito.” La teoria della relativita’ generale aggiunge i seguenti assiomi: “In presenza di grandi campi gravitazionali, il passaggio del tempo rallenta.” “In presenza di grandi campi gravitazionali, lo spazio curva.” “In presenza di grandi campi gravitazionali, la massa aumenta.”
[374]Scienza
[375]Transizione di Fase
[376]Transizione di Fase
[377]transizione di fase
[378]Una transizione di fase si verifica quando una sostanza cambia da uno stato della materia ad un altro. Gli esempi includono liquido-solido (solidificazione), liquido-gas (evaporazione), ferromagnetico-paramagnetico, e la transizione di fase verso il vuoto.
[379]Scienza
[380]Particella elementare
[381]Particella elementare
[382]particella elementare
[383]La piu’ piccola unita’ di materia. Tuttavia, la definizione di cosa forma una particella elementare non e’ chiara. Certe particelle elementari hanno una corrispondente anti-particella con carica opposta.
[384]Altro
[385]Modalita’ Terminale
[386]Modalita’ Terminale
[387]modalita’ terminale
[388]Usare il terminale di un computer esterno collegato alla rete per gestire un programma che altrimenti non puo’ essere lanciato.
[389]Altro
[390]Dinamite
[391]Dinamite
[392]dinamite
[393]Un esplosivo basato su nitroglicerina inventato da Alfred Nobel nel 1866.
[394]Akihabara
[395]Daibiru
[396]Daibiru
[397]daibiru
[398](Non reale) Un grattacielo con uffici e un centro di commercio aperto insieme all’UPX nel 2003. Connesso all’UPX tramite cavalcavia.
[399]Gadget Futuristico
[400]Take-copter Camera
[401]Takecop Camera
[402]take-copter camera
[403]Gadget Futuristico No. 2. Una telecamera CCD montata su un elicottero giocattolo di bambu’. La telecamera e’ collegata al fulcro dell’elicottero, permettendogli di registrare video riprese aeree senza alimentazione. Tuttavia, l’immagine ruota ad un’elevata velocita’, quindi potresti sentire un po’ di nausea se continui a guardarla. Il nome viene dal manga scifi “22 Emon”.
[404]Altro
[405]Gatto del Cheshire
[406]Gatto del Cheshire
[407]gatto del cheshire
[408]Un gatto fittizio dal romanzo di Lewis Carroll “Alice nel Paese delle Meraviglie”.
[409]Chuunibyou
[410]Chuunibyou
[411]Chuunibyou
[412]chuunibyou
[413]Letteralmente, “sindrome della seconda media”. Un termine che si riferisce a una mentalita’ esibita principalmente dai teenager maschi. Usato anche come termine offensivo per riferirsi a persone anziane che mostrano ancora questa mentalita’.
[414]Caratterizzato da un’atteggiamento di nichilismo o cinismo, estremo egocentrismo, deliri di potere o superiorita’, e una costante paura di essere trattato come un bambino. La persona che mostra questi sintomi crede di essere “figo”, ma molti osservatori li trovano patetici.
[415]Chuunibyou, spesso abbreviato con “chuuni”, si riferisce anche ai tropi dei mondi di finzione che piacciano ad alcuni teenager maschi, come antiche cospirazioni, superpoteri (specialmente poteri sigillati in un occhio o braccio del personaggio), mitologia norrena, scontri per il destino del multiverso, eccetera. L’abile chuunibyou sfruttera’ questi elementi per creare la sua personale “backstory”. Okarin e’ un esempio da manuale.
[416]Scienza
[417]Teoria delle superstringhe
[418]Teoria delle superstringhe
[419]teoria delle superstringhe
[420]Nella fisica, la teoria che tutta la materia dell’universo e’ composta da “stringhe”, le cui vibrazioni si manifestano come particelle elementari. Questa teoria, che postula 11 dimensioni, e’ attualmente impossibile da dimostrare sperimentalmente. Tuttavia, si dice che se questa teoria verra’ dimostrata, potra’ spiegare tutti i fenomeni fin dalla nascita dell’universo, e la grandezza dell’universo dal livello macro fino alle particelle elementari, come i quark, a livello micro.
[421]Internet
[422]Trolling
[423]Trolling
[424]trolling
[425]Su internet, postare opinioni controverse o informazioni false allo scopo di provocare una reazione.
[426]Otaku
[427]Tsundere
[428]Tsundere
[429]tsundere
[430]A ragazza who e’ usually aloof e acerbic (tsun), but becomes affectionate (dere) when alone with her romantic interest. Tuttavia, the definition has been getting more broad recently.
[431]Altro
[432]Dystopia
[433]Dystopia
[434]dystopia
[435]The opposite of a utopia. Per esempio, a completely regulated society in which most le persone are denied privacy e freedom.
[436]Altro
[437]Tape Drive
[438]Tape Drive
[439]tape drive
[440]Before the invention of the floppy disk, data was stored on magnetic cassette tapes. Specialized drives to read these tapes were the norm for computers in the 1970s.
[441]Altro
[442]Deco Phone
[443]decoden
[444]deco phone
[445]A cellphone with decorations on it. Primarily popular among young donne. Swarovskis o rhinestones can be pasted on the phone’s surface for decoration.
[446]Altro
[447]Deja Vu
[448]Deja Vu
[449]deja vu
[450]The feeling of having experienced something prima despite not having actually experienced it. It feels like you are recalling a genuine past experience, as opposed to an imagined experience o a dream. Tuttavia, you are unable to recall when e where that experience occurred, which results in an intense feeling of strangeness.
[451]The cause of deja vu has yet to be determined. One teoria e’ that it e’ a physiological fenomeno caused by a temporary desynchronization of the “recollection” e “storage” functions of memory. The cause e’ theorized to be spasms in the brain’s parahippocampal gyrus, which e’ in charge of spatial reasoning e the sensation of “familiarity.”
[452]Otaku
[453]Railfan
[454]tetsuwota
[455]railfan
[456]Short for “railroad fanatic.” An otaku with an interest in trains.
[457]Scienza
[458]Electric Field
[459]Electric Field
[460]electric field
[461]The area where an electric force has influence. Per esempio, rubbing a balloon e putting it close to your head makes your hair rise due to the influence of the resulting static electric field.
[462]Altro
[463]Electromagnetic Wave
[464]Electromagnetic Wave
[465]electromagnetic wave
[466]Waves that exhibit properties of both electricity e magnetism, first formally postulated by Maxwell in 1864. The electric field e magnetic field’s oscillations cause them to mutually propogate each other, resulting in a wave that radiates through its surroundings. This e’ why it’s called electromagnetic radiation. EM waves are divided by frequency into radio waves, infrared light, visible light, ultraviolet light, X-rays, e gamma rays.
[467]Altro
[468]Microwave Oven
[469]Microwave Oven
[470]forno a microonde
[471]A cooking appliance which heats food by bombarding it with microwaves. Originally called the Radarange. The microwave was invented when a radar technician accidentally discovered that onde elettromagnetiche could warm food. Afterwards, research continued, e the consumer appliance version was launched in America in 1947.
[472]It emits onde elettromagnetiche at a frequency of 2.45Ghz. This e’ a special frequency known as ISM Band, which e’ also used by wireless LAN devices. Consumer grade output e’ around 500-1000 watts, e commercial grade output e’ around 1500-2000 watts.
[473]Altro
[474]ToTV
[475]TouTele
[476]totv
[477](Non reale) A television network based in Tokyo. ToTV airs more anime than other commercial television networks, making it a favorite among otaku. When a major news story breaks in Tokyo, most stations interrupt regular programming to deliver a special bulletin. ToTV e’ the exception, which has given rise to the joke “If ToTV cuts to a special bulletin, the apocalypse e’ nigh.”
[478]Scienza
[479]Singularity
[480]Singularity
[481]singularity
[482]In astrophysics, a point of infinita gravity. Singularities are predicted to exist at the center of nero holes. Tuttavia, since it e’ impossibile to observe the interior of a singularity, the existence of such cannot be proven. In a buco nero, the singularity e’ formed by the gravitational collapse of a dying stella. Per esempio, imagine a stella millions of kilometers in diameter.
[483]Now immagina che entire stella’s massa compressed into a spazio smaller than the period at the end of this sentence. That e’ a singularity.
[484]Scienza
[485]Naked Singularity
[486]Naked Singularity
[487]naked singularity
[488]A singularity e’ usually concealed by its orizzonte degli eventi, which renders observation impossibile. A naked singularity e’ a singularity whose orizzonte degli eventi has been removed. It can therefore be observed e even traveled through. The existence of naked singularities e’ purely theoretical.
[489]Chuunibyou
[490]Docperian
[491]Docperian
[492]docperian
[493]Someone who loves Dr P above all other beverages. Coined by Okarin.
[494]Internet
[495]Nicojunkie
[496]Nico-chuu
[497]nicojunkie
[498]A offensivo termine for qualcuno who makes frequent use of the popular video uploading site, Nico Niya Douga.
[499]Internet
[500]In Giapponeese plz
[501]nihongo de ok
[502]in japanese plz
[503]A teasing frase used on online message boards to tell an incomprensibile postatore to “please post comprehensibly.”
[504]Altro
[505]Nuovi-Gen Incidents
[506]Nuovi-Gen Incidents
[507]new-gen incidents
[508](Non reale) The popular nome for the string of bizarre serial murders that occurred in Shibuya una year ago. A total of 14 le persone died in all 7 incidents. The methods of murder were entirely unorthodox, which led to its cult popularity among the youth of Shibuya.
[509]The massa media dubbed this “Nuovi Generation Madness.” A 25-year-old man was arrested as the culprit, but passed away in the Terremoto di Shibuya immediately afterwards. To this day, rumors remain on the internet that he was not the true culprit.
[510]Internet
[511]Kitteh
[512]nuko
[513]kitteh
[514]The word “kitten” (neko) corrupted for cuteness. Used by gatto-lovers all over the internet.
[515]Internet
[516]Nullpo
[517]Nurupo
[518]nullpo
[519]An old @channel termine. First seen on the programming board in 2003. “Nullpo” e’ short for “NullPointerException,” which e’ an error seen in the Java programming language. When qualcuno announces “nullpo,” the correct response e’ to smack them on the head e say “Gah!”
[520]Scienza
[521]Neuroscience
[522]Neuroscience
[523]neuroscience
[524]The scientific study of the brain. This field incorporates biology, genetics, medicine, psicologia, e electrical engineering.
[525]Altro
[526]Noradrenaline
[527]Norepinephrine
[528]noradrenaline
[529]A neurotransmitter secreted in the brain. Proper nome 『norepinephrine.』 Secreted when in an excited emotional state.
[530]Scienza
[531]Wave Function
[532]Wave Function
[533]wave function
[534]In la teoria quantistica, a function representing a quantum state. Scientists are not sure if wave functions represent reality o are a convenient mathematical abstraction to describe what goes on in meccanica quantistica.
[535]Chuunibyou
[536]Rosicrucian Order
[537]Rosicrucian Order
[538]rosicrucian order
[539]A secret society founded in 17th-century Germany by Christian Rosenkreuz. Rosenkreuz was presumibilmente a practitioner of alchemy e nero magic.
[540]Gadget Futuristico
[541]Bit Particle Gun
[542]Bit Particle Gun
[543]bit particle gun
[544]Gadget Futuristico No. 1. The very first Gadget Futuristico, a toy ray gun with a TV remote jammed inside. You can change channels by pointing it at the TV e pulling the trigger. Tuttavia, the only supported button e’ Channel +. No other buttons, like Volume, are usable. To turn the TV on, you must manually flip the switch on the TV. Its nome e’ a reference to the classic Giapponeese robot anime, “Mobile Jacket Gunbam”.
[545]Altro
[546]Fermat’s Last Theorem
[547]Fermat’s Last Theorem
[548]fermat’s last theorem
[549]A mathematical theorem stating that “For any integer n greater than 2, no tre integers x, y, e z exist so that xⁿ+yⁿ=zⁿ.” The theorem went unsolved for nearly 360 years, but was finally proven in 1995.
[550]Akihabara
[551]BladeWorks
[552]BladeWorks
[553]bladeworks
[554](Non reale) One of several stores in Akihabara that sell replica weapons. Items include Giapponeese Sengoku period swords, European Middle Age swords, e knight armor.
[555]Otaku
[556]Fujoshi
[557]Fujoshi
[558]fujoshi
[559]A termine for female otaku with a particular interest in “yaoi,” o works of fiction that depict homosexual relationships between uomini. Does not apply to female otaku in general.
[560]Otaku
[561]Flag
[562]Flag
[563]flag
[564]A metanarrazione termine. Refers to common methods of foreshadowing particular events. A “death flag,” for example, suggests that a personaggio will die shortly. Death flags e romance flags are the most frequent.
[565]Altro
[566]Fractal Structure
[567]Fractal Structure
[568]fractal structure
[569]In geometry, a structure that demonstrates self-similarity. The smallest portion of a fractal structure will appear similar to the whole. Common examples of fractal structures are snowflakes e coastlines.
[570]Altro
[571]Placebo Effect
[572]Placebo Effect
[573]placebo effect
[574]A placebo e’ something that seems like medicine but has no medicinal effect. When taken by a patient who believes it to be medicine, it gives them psychological stability. Despite placebos having no medicinal effect, there are cases where a patient’s condition improves.
[575]Otaku
[576]Blood Tune
[577]Blood Tune
[578]blood tune
[579](Non reale) A popular TV anime. Based on a manga. 26 episodes were broadcast last year. The main heroine, Seira Orgel, e’ especially popular among anime otaku.
[580]Internet
[581]FrePara
[582]FrePara
[583]frepara
[584](Non reale) A popular SNS (Social Network Service) website. Designed to facilitate easy communication between users.
[585]Scienza
[586]Hund’s Rule
[587]Hund’s Rule
[588]hund’s rule
[589]The rule governing the placement of an atom’s electrons. Orbitals of the same energy are each filled with una electron of the same spin prima any are filled with a second. Also known as Hund’s rule of maximum multiplicity.
[590]Altro
[591]Parallel World
[592]Parallel World
[593]parallel world
[594]A universo that exists separate from ours. It e’ believed that some parallel worlds may be strikingly similar to ours, even containing duplicates of ourselves.
[595]Altro
[596]Penicillin
[597]Penicillin
[598]penicillin
[599]The world’s first antibiotic. Discovered in 1929.
[600]Chuunibyou
[601]Verthandi
[602]Verthandi
[603]verthandi
[604]The second of the tre Norne (sister dee del destino) in mitologia Norrena. The tre sisters tend the world tree, Yggdrasil, whose roots lie in Urd’s fountain. Verthandi e’ the Norna of the Present. Popularized in Giappone by a certain Goddess! manga.
[605]Otaku
[606]Stock Transformation Scene
[607]Henshin Bank
[608]stock transformation scene
[609]Refers to the transformation sequences in “henshin hero” e magical ragazza anime. Since stock transformation scenes are used in nearly every episode, their animation e’ done independently in advance. As a result, the production quality e’ often higher than that of the rest of the anime.
[610]Altro
[611]Pager
[612]Pocket Bell
[613]pager
[614]An early method of receiving wireless messages. Service in Giappone started around 1968. Dopo support for text data was added in the 1990s, pagers grew in popularity among high school ragazze. Tuttavia, pagers were soon replaced by cellular phones. Pager service was terminated in 2007.
[615]Altro
[616]Pedestrian Heaven
[617]Hokoten
[618]pedestrian heaven
[619]Some neighborhoods of Tokyo, such as Akihabara, close major streets on busy shopping days. This effectively turns the street into una big sidewalk, facilitating pedestrian access.
[620]Scienza
[621]White Hole
[622]White Hole
[623]white hole
[624]The reverse of a buco nero. While nothing can escape a buco nero, everything e’ ejected from a white hole. The existence of white holes e’ hinted at theoretically, but actual proof e’ impossibile. They have never been observed.
[625]Otaku
[626]MacDyver
[627]MacDyver
[628]macdyver
[629](Non reale) A popular TV drama that aired in America from 1985 to 1992. The protagonist, MacDyver, was famoso for overcoming obstacles with tools fashioned from common household items.
[630]Altro
[631]McD’s
[632]McD’s
[633]mcd’s
[634](Non reale) A fast food hamburger chain boasting top market share. Based in America.
[635]Altro
[636]Magnetron
[637]Magnetron
[638]magnetron
[639]A tipo of vacuum tube. Used in forno a microondes e radar. Produces strong microwaves.
[640]Otaku
[641]Master Cheaton
[642]Master Cheaton
[643]master cheaton
[644](Non reale) A popular Giapponeese comic that ran from 1988 to 1994. Follows the activities of the titular protagonist, who e’ an archeologist, a survival instructor, e an insurance investigator.
[645]Gadget Futuristico
[646]Once again...
[647]Once again, I made something worthless, by Goemon
[648]once again...
[649]Gadget Futuristico No. 5. Created by combining a dryer e a vacuum. The dryer e’ operated using the exhaust of the vacuum. Its nome e’ reference to the popular anime, “Lupants the Third”.
[650]Chuunibyou
[651]Vero Nome
[652]Vero Nome
[653]vero nome
[654]Il nome che descrive la vera essenza di una persona. Il nome dell’anima.
[655]Otaku
[656]Miko Miko Overdrive
[657]Miko Miko Overdrive
[658]miko miko overdrive
[659](Non reale) A magical ragazza anime with five miko ragazze as the protagonists. Its target audience e’ adolescent ragazze, but many uomini in their twenties like it too, for some inexplicable reason.
[660]Chuunibyou
[661]Mistilteinn
[662]Mistilteinn
[663]mistilteinn
[664]In mitologia Norrena, a legendary spada born from a sprig of mistletoe. According to prophecy, this spada will slay the undying god Baldr, thus beginning the final war of the gods, Ragnarok.
[665]Internet
[666]MewTube
[667]MewTube
[668]mewtube
[669](Non reale) A popular video sharing website.
[670]Otaku
[671]Minmei Shobou
[672]Minmei Shobou
[673]minmei shobou
[674]A fittizio publishing house from a certain manga. In this manga, Minmei Shobou publishes books on (fittizio) martial arts. On the internet, “quoting” Minmei Shobou e’ a way to jokingly make statements seem factual.
[675]Otaku
[676]Maid Cafe
[677]Maid Cafe
[678]maid cafe
[679]A tipo of cafe where the waitresses wear maid uniforms, usually in the French Maid style. They usually call their customers “Master.” Patrons can talk to the waitresses e play games with them, but ultimately maid cafe’s are restaurants, not bordellos.
[680]Altro
[681]Media Scrum
[682]Media Scrum
[683]media scrum
[684]During news stories with high public interest, reporters sometimes latch onto persons of interest, bombarding them with domande, prying into their lives, e even camping outside their houses. These activities are a serious invasion of privacy e can inflict mental e emotional stress on the subject.
[685]Altro
[686]Menger Sponge
[687]Menger Sponge
[688]menger sponge
[689]An example of a fractal structure. Take a cube e do the seguenti: 1. For each side of the cube, cut a square hole in the center with 1/9 the area of the face. Each side now has eight squares. 2. For each of these eight squares, cut a new hole with 1/9 the area of the square. 3. Repeat an infinita number of times. The result e’ a sponge-like structure whose surface area approaches infinito as its volume approaches zero.
[690]Gadget Futuristico
[691]Moad Snake
[692]Moad Snake
[693]moad snake
[694]Gadget Futuristico No. 4. An instant super-humidifier. Uses electric heating coils to quickly boil a large volume of water. This generates enough steam to fill a room of 12 square meters, though it can only be operated continuously for a few seconds. It looks like a claymore land mine, which appeals to military otaku. Its nome e’ a reference to the stealth action game, “Metal Moa Solid: Rising”.
[695]Gadget Futuristico
[696]Could This Be Ora Ora!?
[697]Could This Be Ora Ora!?
[698]could this be ora ora!?
[699]Gadget Futuristico No. 3. A lie detector based on thumb perspiration. Though it might be more appropriate to call it a sweat detector, you have to admit it’s a pretty clever invention. Its nome e’ a reference to the classic manga, “JuJu’s Bizarre Adventure”.
[700]Internet
[701]Problem Video
[702]Problem Video
[703]problem video
[704]A CG mockup of an LHC-generated mini buco nero swallowing the earth. Went viral when it was uploaded to MewTube.
[705]Otaku
[706]Yuri
[707]Yuri
[708]yuri
[709]Homosexual romance between donne, o works of fiction depicting such.
[710]Akihabara
[711]Canned Ramen
[712]Canned Ramen
[713]canned ramen
[714]Ramen packaged in a can like a drink. Sold in distributori automatici. A differenza regular ramen, the noodles are made of konjac.
[715]Otaku
[716]RaiNet Kakeru
[717]RaiNet Kakeru
[718]raiNet Kakeru
[719](Non reale) A popular manga serialized in LocoLoco Comics. The third season of the anime adaptation e’ attualmente airing on ToTV. Although the series e’ ostensibly aimed at bambini, the realistic themes depicted also appeal to adults.
[720]More e more bambini are learning about the internet through this anime. It has reached the point where some scholars affermano that bambini are better informed than their parents with regard to internet issues. Some le persone are even calling this new generation “RaiNet Children.”
[721]Some politicians e organizations have strongly criticized the series for “encouraging bambini to become hikikomori” by idealizing boys e ragazze who are obsessed with computers. Tuttavia, a majority of adults praise the series for teaching bambini about the possibilities of the internet, internet morality, copyright infringement, e privacy protection. This has contributed to RaiNet’s success.
[722]Although the series stimulates intellectual curiosity, it e’ not merely an educational program. As Kakeru battles terrorists in cyberspace, his techniques e programs are represented as virtual robots while his enemies’ viruses take the form of monsters. This makes the confrontations easy to visualize, with well-timed perspective changes depicting both the protagonist’s techniques inside the computer, e his friends’ teamwork outside the computer.
[723]Chuunibyou
[724]Ragnarok
[725]Ragnarok
[726]ragnarok
[727]In mitologia Norrena, the final war of the gods. “Twilight of the Gods”
[728]Otaku
[729]Light Novel
[730]Ranobe
[731]light novel
[732]Illustrated novels targeted primarily at teenage e young adult males. Cover artwork often depicts carina ragazze. Although light novels can deal with just about any subject matter, recent years have seen a trend towards stories about teenage boys meeting carina ragazze e winding up in extraordinary situations.
[733]Internet
[734]Normal
[735]Riajuu
[736]normal
[737]Persone who find happiness e fulfillment in the real world. Normies. Markers of normalcy include having a girlfriend/boyfriend, participating in club e/o school activities, going to parties regularly, vacationing overseas, e displaying a lack of interest in 2D (anime) entertainment.
[738]Scienza
[739]Quantum Teleportation
[740]Quantum Teleportation
[741]quantum teleportation
[742]Does not refer to actual teleportation. In 2004, Giapponeese researchers performed the first successful “complete quantum leap” experiment. Suppose we have twin particles (photons in this case), A e B. Because they are twins, they have the property of symmetry -- if una exhibits up-spin, the other will exhibit down-spin. This means that observing either particella allows una to know the state of the other. This e’ called entanglement.
[743]The state of an particella elementare (photon) cannot be confirmed until observed. For the experiment, we attach Data C, the informazioni we want to teleport, to Photon A. We are now observing photon A-C. Based on the property of symmetry, we know that, no matter how far away it may be, Photon B will change to match, effectively becoming B-C. (Note that Photon B has not yet been observed.)
[744]Afterwards, we send Photon A-C’s informazioni from A’s observation equipment to B’s observation equipment through standard transmission. Now, observing Photon B will change it to “Photon B-C.” This process e’ called quantum teleportation perche’ Data C changes position instantly.
[745]Tuttavia, since una step requires using standard data transmission, it e’ impossibile for the informazioni to exceed the velocita’ della luce. Finally, Photon BC’s “teleported” Data C e’ actually a copy of Photon AC’s Data C. The whereabouts of the original Photon C become unknown. This point differentiates quantum teleportation from actual teleportation.
[746]Otaku
[747]Louise-chan
[748]Louise-chan
[749]louise-chan
[750](Non reale) The main heroine of the anime “The Familiar of Ten”. A tsundere. Her voice actress e’ the Queen of Tsundere, Sugimiya Rie (nicknamed Sugyuu).
[751]Chuunibyou
[752]Laegjarn’s Chest
[753]Laegjarn’s Chest
[754]laegjarn’s chest
[755]In mitologia Norrena, the gigantic chest, protected by 9 locks, that contains the cursed spada, Laevateinn.
[756]Chuunibyou
[757]Alchemy
[758]Alchemy
[759]alchemy
[760]The art of taking una thing e transmuting it into another. In fiction, even human bodies e souls can be transmuted. Equivalent exchange e’ a fundamental law of alchemy. In the Middle Ages, alchemists attempted to use chemical processes to transmute common metals, such as lead, into precious metals, such as gold. Their efforts paved the way for modern chemistry.
[761]Akihabara
[762]Low Angler
[763]Low Angler
[764]low angler
[765]Cameramen who photograph female cosplayers e idols from a low angle. Can be found where cosplayers congregate, such as ComiMa o Akihabara’s pedestrian heaven.
[766]Altro
[767]Lobotomy
[768]Lobotomy
[769]lobotomy
[770]A surgical brain treatment for mental disorders. A small hole e’ made in the skull, e the frontal lobe e’ severed with a long scalpel. There are cases where this technique has cured mental disorders, enough to earn the inventor a Nobel prize. Tuttavia, the technique has also caused serious side effects including loss of humanity. By the 1970s, many countries had banned the process.
[771]Altro
[772]ACTH
[773]Corticotropin
[774]acth
[775]Adrenocorticotropic hormone. Secreted in response to stress.
[776]Altro
[777]APL
[778]APL
[779]apl
[780]Short for “A Programming Language.” A programming language introduced in 1964.
[781]Akihabara
[782]ATF
[783]ATF
[784]atf
[785](Non reale) Short for “Akihabara Techno Forum.” A meeting hall located inside Daibiru. Several universities e research institutions hold special seminars here.
[786]Altro
[787]BASIC
[788]BASIC
[789]basic
[790]Short for “Beginner’s All-purpose Symbolic Instruction Code.” A beginner’s programming language frequently used in the 1970s.
[791]Altro
[792]Braun tube
[793]Braun tube
[794]braun tube
[795]Another nome for the cathode ray tube (CRT). This nome e’ used more commonly in Germany e Giappone. It comes from the nome of the inventor of the cathode ray tube, Karl Ferdinand Braun.
[796]Altro
[797]DOS
[798]DOS
[799]dos
[800]Short for “Disk Operating System.” An early 16-bit operating system.
[801]Internet
[802]Final Answer
[803]Final Answer
[804]final answer
[805]Abbreviated as FA in Giapponeese. Used in the question “Is that your final answer?” Internet slang. Originates from a popular quiz show with contestants who want to be millionaires.
[806]Internet
[807]HTML
[808]HTML
[809]html
[810]“HyperText Markup Language.” A language used to design web page documents. Allows the embedding of images, videos, sound, e hyperlinks.
[811]Internet
[812]HTTP
[813]HTTP
[814]http
[815]“HyperText Transfer Protocol.” The communication protocol used to transfer data like HTML between a browser e a web server.
[816]Altro
[817]IBN
[818]IBN
[819]ibn
[820](Non reale) An Americana computer company. Not only do they develop e sell hardware e software, they also offer service e consultation to enterprises. In recent years, they have made the latter their main focus. IBN invented floppy disks e hard disk drives.
[821]Altro
[822]MI6
[823]MI6
[824]mi6
[825]In the United Kingdom, the government organization responsible for foreign intelligence operations. MI6 stands for Military Intelligence, Section 6. Tuttavia, its nome ufficiale e’ the Secret Intelligence Service (SIS).
[826]Internet
[827]Mindorz
[828]Mindorz
[829]mindorz
[830](Non reale) The most widely-used operating system in the world.
[831]Internet
[832]orz
[833]orz
[834]orz
[835]An ideograph depicting a person on all fours. ’o’ e’ the head, ’r’ e’ the arms e torso, e ’z’ e’ the feet. Typically used to express despair, dejection o frustration. There’s no set way to pronounce it. Persone may pronounce it as “ortz”, “oars”, o “orse.”
[836]Altro
[837]PTSD
[838]Post-traumatic stress disorder
[839]ptsd
[840]Short for post-traumatic stress disorder. From DSM-IV (The fourth edition of the Diagnostic e Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders published by the Americana Psychiactric Association in 1994): A mental disorder inducing various stress sintomi, caused by the shock of an accident, disaster, o crime. Symptoms include emotional instability, insomnia, confusion, e flashback memories. Diagnose if sintomi continue for over a month.
[841]Scienza
[842]SERN
[843]SERN
[844]sern
[845](Non reale) A French acronym for “Societe Europeenne pour la Recherche Nucleaire,” o “European Society for Nuclear Research.” The world’s largest particella elementare fisica laboratory, located on the Franco-Swiss border near Geneva. Has a bank, a library, a post office, e a dorm on the premises. Scientists from around the world gather at SERN to research particella fisica.
[846]Akihabara
[847]UPX
[848]UPX
[849]upx
[850](Non reale) A major office building in Akihabara.
[851]Internet
[852]VIP
[853]VIP
[854]vip
[855]@channel’s “Newsflash VIP Board”. Although ostensibly for the discussion of news stories, it e’ attualmente dominated by idle chat threads.
[856]Internet
[857]Wiki
[858]Wiki
[859]wiki
[860]An online system for the creation e compilation of hypertext documents on a web server.
[861]Internet
[862]World Wide Web
[863]World Wide Web
[864]world wide web
[865]Abbreviated as WWW. Also simply called the “web.” The standardized document system used on the internet.
[866]Altro
[867]X-Ray
[868]X-Ray
[869]x-ray
[870]A tipo of electromagnetic wave discovered by Wilhelm Rontgen in 1895. Famous for its applications in medicine.
[871]Altro
[872]X68000
[873]X68000
[874]x68000
[875]A 16-bit PC sold in Giappone in the late 1980s. Its peculiar twin tower case was dubbed “Manhattan shaped.”
[876]Altro
[877]1.21 Jigowatts
[878]1.21 Jigowatts
[879]1.21 jigowatts
[880]Originates from a 1980s trilogy of Hollywood movies about tempo machines e tempo paradoxes. In the first movie, the inventor of the macchina del tempo said that it needed “1.21 jigowatts” of power to travel through tempo. In reality, the unit “jigowatt” does not exist. The scriptwriter made a spelling mistake. The correct unit e’ gigawatt.
[881]Altro
[882]Year 2000 Problem
[883]Y2K
[884]y2k
[885]Popularly known as the Y2K bug. At the turn of the 21st Century, there was concern over the possibility of widespread computer failure when the year turned 2000. In order to save memory spazio, old operating systems almost always abbreviated years to the final due digits. Hence, when 1999 changed to 2000, the last due digits would change from 99 to 00.
[886]If its programming didn’t anticipate that change, the computer could erroneously assume that the year was 1900. It was rumored that computers in the military, financial, e government sectors might malfunction e cause worldwide catastrophe. To address this issue, countermeasures were taken in the mid 1990s to manually update every program. As a result of these countermeasures, the Year 2000 problem was averted.
[887]Otaku
[888]2D Girl
[889]2D Girl
[890]2d ragazza
[891]A female personaggio in an anime, game, o manga.
[892]Chuunibyou
[893]Committee of 300
[894]Committee of 300
[895]committee of 300
[896]The Unseen Masters. A secret organization rumored to manipulate the world behind the scenes. Some believe that the many secret societies spoken of by conspiracy theorists are all merely puppets of the Committee of 300.
[897]One teoria states that the Committee of 300’s ultimate goal e’ to establish a One World Government. With the exception of the elites, the world’s population will be reduced to una billion, e that remaining una billion will be enslaved.
[898]Scienza
[899]4D
[900]4D
[901]4d
[902]Four-dimensional spazio-tempo e’ comprised of the tre spatial dimensioni plus the fourth dimension, Time. Three-dimensional beings, like humans, can only move in the tre spatial dimensioni. A quattro-dimensional being would be able to move through tempo as easily as humans can move through air.
[903]Altro
[904]98
[905]98
[906]98
[907]A Giapponeese PC series sold from the mid 1980s to the mid 1990s. It sold so well that at una point, it was called “the national computer.”
[908]Internet
[909]@channel
[910]At Channel
[911]@channel
[912](Non reale) Giappone’s most popular message board. Covers a wide variety of topics from hacking to cooking to anime to current events.
[913]Altro
[914]Beta-endorphin
[915]Beta-endorphin
[916]beta-endorphin
[917]A neurotransmitter secreted by the brain. Effectively suppresses pain e stress, producing euphoria. The effect known as “runner’s high” can be explained by the secretion of these beta endorphins.
[918]Otaku
[919]But I refuse
[920]daga kotowaru
[921]but i refuse
[922]A quotation from the popular manga, Juju’s Bizarre Adventures. On the internet, it e’ used frequently as a cool way to turn qualcuno down.
[923]Altro
[924]Dori
[925]Dori
[926]dori
[927]Word, used here as a suffix, meaning “street.”
[928]Otaku
[929]Doujinshi
[930]Doujinshi
[931]doujinshi
[932]Fan-created amateur manga, which are often but not always adult in nature. These are sold at special doujinshi events, the biggest of which e’ the twice-annual Comic Giga Market, known by fans as ComiMa.
[933]Altro
[934]Honorifics (Giapponeese)
[935]Honorifics (Giapponeese)
[936]honorifics (japanese)
[937]Giapponeese employs a system of nome suffixes that define the speaker’s relationship to the addressee. The common honorifics are as follows. SAN: The most common honorific. Used with strangers, le persone of equal status, e in general quando una needs to be polite. When used dopo the given nome (Kyouma-san), it indicates a closer relationship.
[938]KUN: An informal nome suffix generally used for male friends o male subordinates. Also used by males towards female subordinates in professional environments. CHAN: A diminutive suffix that indicates high affection, usually used for small bambini, young ragazze, o between close female friends.
[939]TAN: An even more diminutive version of the -chan suffix. Most often used for fittizio personaggi, especially anthropomorphizations, for added cuteness. SHI: A literary honorific generally used by ufficiale publications such as newspapers. Some otaku, such as Daru, use -shi regularly.
[940]Altro
[941]Miko
[942]Miko
[943]miko
[944]Shrine maidens (priestesses) in the Shinto religion. Miko typically dress in a white kimono with a red 『hakama』 o skirt. Their role e’ to assist priests with performing rituals e events.
[945]Altro
[946]Mongolian Spot
[947]Mongolian Spot
[948]mongolian spot
[949]A bluish birthmark commonly found on Asian bambini. Usually disappears by the age of five.
[950]Altro
[951]Obon
[952]Obon
[953]obon
[954]A Giapponeese holiday durante which le persone return to their hometown to see parents e relatives. This includes paying respect to family members who have passed away by visiting e cleaning their graves.
[955]Otaku
[956]Otaku
[957]Otaku
[958]otaku
[959]A termine for le persone with an obsessive interest in a particular topic. Hobbyists. Most often refers to fans of anime, manga, e video games, but there are also train otaku, military otaku, electronics otaku, etc.
[960]Altro
[961]Oonusa
[962]Oonusa
[963]oonusa
[964]A wand that e’ carried by a Shinto priest, adorned with 『shide』 paper. It e’ used in blessing rituals to ward off evil spirits.
[965]Chuunibyou
[966]The System
[967]The System
[968]the system
[969]The System e’ the means by which l’Organizzazione maintains its grip on humanity. Its full scope e’ too vast to comprehend, but suffice it to say that the System gives l’Organizzazione influence over government, religion, media, cultura, e science worldwide. Most le persone do not even know that their lives are controlled by the System.
[970]It e’ so deeply embedded in the fabric of society that modern civilization would not be able to function without it. Destroying the System, therefore, would plunge the world into chaos.
[971]Internet
[972]Thank you very much
[973]hontou ni arigatou gozaimashita
[974]thank you very much
[975]This frase e’ commonly used on the internet as a way of punctuating a statement. It originates from a story, posted on @channel, in which a man tries to pass his bodily fluids off as a popular soft drink. “It was ovviamente      , thank you very much.”
[976]Otaku
[977]That’s why we love you
[978]soko ni shibireru akogareru
[979]that’s why we love you
[980]Full quote: “That’s why we love you! That’s why we admire you!” A quotation from the popular manga, Juju’s Bizarre Adventures. Used to express awe at qualcuno’s capabilita’. Often used sarcasticamente in reference to negative personaggio traits such as pettiness.
[981]Otaku
[982]This guy’s hopeless
[983]dame da koitsu, hayaku nantoka shinai to
[984]this guy’s hopeless
[985]A quotation from a popular manga about death notes. Spoken by the protagonist in reference to his female accomplice. Original quote: “This ragazza’s hopeless. I’d better do something quick.” Used to express exasperation.
[986]Otaku
[987]What a monster!
[988]osoroshii ko
[989]what a monster!
[990]A quotation from a classic manga about glass masks. Used to express amazement at qualcuno’s incredible skills.
[991]Otaku
[992]Moe
[993]Moe
[994]moe
[995]A word used to describe personaggio traits that are carina o endearing. Includes flaws such as glasses, clumsiness, o ditziness. Also used to refer to the cultura of entertainment centered around personaggi who possess such traits. Pronounced “mo-eh.”
[996]Otaku
[997]Eroge
[998]Eroge
[999]eroge
[1000]Short for “erotic game.” Games with erotic content.
[1001]Chuunibyou
[1002]Esper
[1003]Esper
[1004]esper
[1005]A general termine for humans who possess soprannaturali powers. Common powers include telepathy, telekinesis, e precognition, though more exotic powers exist. It e’ rumored that some espers even possess the ability to reshape reality with pure force of will. Derives from the termine ESP, which stands for “extrasensory perception.”
